



FRONT END DEVELOPER

☑ inr.varun89@gmail.com

Attps://nrvarun.xyz

ໍາດ https://linkedin.com/in/varunnr

I am a Front end engineer with 5+ years of experience and with a great focus on UX rather than a functional UI, i believe a functional UI can only give users a normal experience and a UI with great focus on UX on all the big and little details of the UI can give a wow experience.

- Lead and architected multiple responsive scalable projects with the latest tech stack..
- React Nanodegree Certified from Udacity (https://graduation.udacity.com/confirm/4N9GG7SA).
- Solid understanding of JavaScript(ES5/ES6+) and the ability to pick up any framework quickly.
- Experience with Restful and GraphQL APIs integrations.
- Proficient with Cross-Browser compatibility issues and ways to work around such issues.
- Proficient in developing Scalable and modular Architecture apps using React, Next.js etc..
- Proficient with CSS-in-JS, Styled JSX, Styled components and CSS modules approaches for modern application architecture at scale.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

₼ Wall Dec. 2021 - Currently

- Built and shipped scalable modules like Rekt Meter (https://www.wall.app/rekt-meter), Onboarding flow etc...
- Complete Responsibiliy of End to End feature development including performance assessment, Responsive Development and page optimizations.
- Tech Stack: React 18/Nextjs, Redux, React Query, Axios, Styled Components.

Summary or impact about the role/company:

Responsible for Scalable development of Product Features from scratch to optimized deployments with caching.

Freelance UI Consultant

freelance

苗 Jul. 2021 - February 2022

- Complete Responsibiliy of End to End feature development including performance assessment, Responsive Development and page optimizations.
- UI development of a React native mobile app for a Waste management platform.
- Working directly with executives for API integrations using Axios, React Query for a more control and cache optimized API integration.
- Developing Marketing websites with fluid animations using custom Javascript, CSS and familiar with GreenSock
- Tech Stack: React, Nextjs, Javascript, HTML, CSS etc...

Summary or impact about the role/company:

Responsible for Built and Shipped responsive and optimized marketing websites, web apps with good page score.

Senior Frontend Developer

Lollypop UX UI Studio

🛗 Aug. 2020 - May 2021

- Responsible for leading the team and also for developing fully responsive, quality checked websites and web apps using latest tech stack like JavaScript(ES5/ES6+), PUG, SASS, React.js, Next.js.
- Lead and Architected the revamping of the customer facing B2C/B2B e-commerce portal for Tata Steel's unique
- digital intervention to provide 360 degree solutions to its ECA customers. Developed and tested feature-rich, fully-responsive, optimized and Scalable code for all the modules. (Onboarding,

Products Catalogue, Transactions, Payment, Profile, Enquiries/Orders management etc...).

 Worked with a team of developers and designers in an Agile environment to bring designs to light with a feedback loop in place.

Projects:

- DigECA - https://digeca.tatasteel.com

Summary or impact about the role/company:

Lead and build consumer facing and business facing applications using react and also making sure the load times are optimal and does not affect the user experience.

Frontend Developer

Lollypop UX UI Studio

苗 Mar. 2017 - Aug. 2020

- RunAdam:
- Developed a social networking platform for Athletes called RunAdam which was more or less like linkedin but for the Sports Professionals. The primary focus is to build a global network of professionals, athletes, and other
- Lead and Architected the development of functional, Reusable and Scalable components for the entire Runadam web app. Doing extensive cross browser testing and also assessing the page performance by using the Chrome Devtools and Lighthouse for performance optimization.
- Hexaware: (https://hexaware.com/)
- Responsible for developing 33 unique pages and a Component library of 30 reusable, scalable and independent components for the development of all other pages. The project was developed using the Pug template engine, SCSS, ES6 and jQuery.
- Right Side up (https://rightsideup.com/)
- A marketing website for a US client, the website was developed using webpack4, ES6, SCSS and PUG Template engine. The interactions were custom coded using GreenSock Platform(GSAP 3). Strict performance assessments were done in order to make sure the site loads fast and gives the best experience to the user.

Summary or impact about the role/company:

Responsible for leading the team and also for developing fully responsive, quality checked websites and web apps.

Software Engineer

f goboxme

📛 Sep. 2015 - Apr. 2016

 Responsible for developing the consumer facing UI for the Angular Web app using Material Design and RESTful API integrations using axios.

Summary or impact about the role/company:

Responsible for developing the UI for the goboxme b2b warehousing app that helps businesses with logistics.

Freelance Developer

freelance • Handled web development services for multiple clients and shipped out marketing websites which are responsive

Apr. 2015 - Sep 2015

and pixel perfect.

SKILLS

UI Engineer

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Reactjs, Object-Oriented Programming, Responsive Web Development, Cross-Browser compatibility, Build Automation tools, Scalable and Optimized Development, API integrations.

Tools/Frameworks

Styled Components/CSS-in-JS, Nextjs, Redux, React Query, Framer motion, GreenSock, Vercel, Sentry, Lighthouse, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Figma, Chrome Dev tools, Webpack/

Languages

Gulp,

React Nanodegree Program

EDUCATION

Udacity

2019

Web development

Udacity

Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham

= 2014

Masters in Computer Application

2011 - 2014